(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ここはとある世界のお花屋さん
This is a flower shop in a certain world.
そんな花屋には七色に輝く...
In that flower shop, there was a single flower...
...一輪のお花がいました
...that shone with the colors of the rainbow.
彼女はこの花屋が大好きでした
She loved this flower shop.
花屋では毎日たくさんの花たちが
Every day at the flower shop,
美しく咲き誇ります
many flowers bloom beautifully.
そんなお花たちを見て
The customers see those flowers...
笑顔になるお客さん
...and smile.
彼女はその笑顔が何よりも大好きでした
She loved those smiles more than anything.
でもここはお花屋さん
But this is a flower shop.
そんな咲き誇ったお花たちも一輪また一輪と
Those blooming flowers, one by one,
お客さんと一緒に旅立っていきました
departed with the customers.
笑顔で旅立っていくお花とお客さんを見て
Watching the flowers and customers depart with smiles,
彼女はとても幸せでした
she was very happy.
「あれ、でも、だけど私は…？」
"Oh, but, wait, what about me...?"
今日も笑顔で旅立っていくお花たち
Today, too, the flowers depart with smiles.
「あのお花は大きくて綺麗だな、
"That flower is big and beautiful,
あの子の色は素敵だな、
that one's color is lovely,
あれ？私ってどんな花なんだろう…？」
wait? What kind of flower am I...?"
自分の魅力がわからなくなってしまった彼女は
Having lost sight of her own charm,
ついに自分の色を見失ってしまいました
she eventually lost sight of her own color.
そう簡単な祈りだった
It was such a simple prayer
綻びはだんだんとき消える感嘆
The seams gradually fade, a sigh of admiration
今からドンドンが上がるから
Since things will liven up from now on
静から会場を彩りさようなら
Decorating the venue from the silence, goodbye
ロウワー
作詞・作曲：ぬゆり
Lower
Lyrics & Composition: nulut
見失う程の言の葉が
跪き出端をまた増えて繋ぎ
Words so numerous you lose sight of them
Kneeling down, they increase and connect again at the start
後ろめたさからくる
Coming from a sense of guilt
浸りたい心とは裏腹に
旋律に込めて胸の中が
Contrary to the heart that wants to be immersed
The inside of the chest is filled with melody
降りない意味に寄る
Depending on an unyielding meaning
受け止めたい言葉が
自分さえ変えられず
The words I want to accept
Can't even change me
持ち出したそれをまた退け
Pushing away what was brought out again
霞んだ声は空回り
The hazy voice spins its wheels
何を言うべきか分からなくて
Not knowing what should be said
感じてたモノが遠く彼方へ消えた
What I felt vanished into the far distance
同じようで違らなんて　ふつがう
It's the same, yet different—how inconvenient
いつまで行こうか　どこまで行けるのか
How long shall we go? How far can we go?
まだ始まっちゃいないんだよ　もっと
It hasn't even started yet, more
僕らが離れるなら
If we are to part
僕らが迷うなら
If we are to lose our way
その度に何回も繋がれる様に
So that we can connect many times over
ここにいてくれるなら
If you will stay here
離さずにいられたら
If I could keep from letting go
誰も知らない感覚に救われて
Saved by a sensation that no one knows
待ったがなる
Wait, it's a stop
Hold up, my enemy goes
ここを出ていこうか
Shall we get out of here?
ずっとの言い願いを
A wish made for eternity
同じ様に、同じ様に呟く
Muttered the same way, the same way
どこから聞こうか
Where should I start listening?
何を見失うか
What will I lose sight of?
たったそれだけが
Just that alone...
もう動けない
...can no longer move
僕らが作れるなら
If we can create it
それ以上ないなら
If there is nothing more than that
その度に何回も
Every time, again and again
逃げ出せる様に
So that we can escape
心が守れる様に
So that our hearts can be protected
奪われない様に
So that they aren't stolen away
互いに託して
Entrusting each other
身体預けてよ
Surrender your body
君と流す
Shedding tears with you
君と笑う
Laughing with you
君と怒る
Getting angry with you
君と歌う
Singing with you
君と踊る
Dancing with you
君とはまる
Being obsessed with you
いつまで続くだろうと
Wondering how long it will last
同じ様に、同じ様に呟く
Muttered the same way, the same way
今は忘れないよう
So as not to forget for now
刻まれた空気を
The atmosphere etched into me
これから何度思い出すのだろう
How many times will I remember it from now on?
僕らだけが
Only we...
僕らが離れるなら
...if we are to drift apart
僕らが惑うなら
If we are to be bewildered
その度に何回も繋がれる様に
So that we can be connected every time, again and again
ここに居てくれるなら
If you would stay here
離れず居られたら
If we could stay together
まだ誰も知らない
A feeling that no one knows yet
感覚で僕ら生きている
Is how we are living
全てを確かめて
Checking everything
正しくして
And setting it right
はい、ロゼ、ガールズたち、ありがとう！
Yes! Rosé, girls, thank you!
ありがとうね！お疲れ様！
Thank you! Good work!
ありがと、ありがとー。
Thank you, thank you.
ということで、お待たせしましたかな？
So, did I keep you waiting?
みんな、見えてる？聞こえてる？
Everyone, can you see me? Can you hear me?
ホロライブ所属の癒し系ハーフエルフ
The healing-type half-elf of hololive,
アキロゼこと、アキ...アキ...
AkiRose, a.k.a. Aki... Aki...
決まんなかったけど、もう一回いくね。
That didn't land well, let me try again.
アキロゼこと、アキ・ローゼンタールです！
AkiRose, a.k.a. Aki Rosenthal!
ハロー、ハロー、ハロー、アローナ！
Hello, hello, hello, Alona!
はい！アキロゼ生誕祭2025へようこそ！
Yes! Welcome to AkiRose Birthday Festival 2025!
今年のテーマは「Your True Colors」とさせていただきまして
This year's theme is "Your True Colors"...
アキロゼが今まで生誕祭でよくやっていたミュージカル形式とは
...and it's a bit different from the musical format I usually do.
ちょっと趣向を変えて、違う感じの生誕祭を今年はやってみようかなと思って
I thought I'd change things up and try a different kind of birthday festival this year.
去年とはまた変わったライブにしたいなと思っております。
I want to make it a live performance that's different from last year's.
なんと今年は色んなゲストの方が、盛りだくさん登場してくれるということなので
We have a lot of different guests appearing this year...
ぜひ色んな人を楽しみにしててね！
...so please look forward to seeing everyone!
今回のアキロゼの生誕祭のハッシュタグはこちら！
The hashtag for this AkiRose Birthday Festival is this!
#アキロゼ生誕祭2025 ポストなどでじゃんじゃん呟いてください！
#AkiRoseBirthday2025 Please tweet away with this hashtag!
え？何？アキロゼが可愛すぎてスクショが止まらない？
Eh? What? AkiRose is so cute you can't stop taking screenshots?
そうだよねー、そうだよねー。気づいた人いるかな？
I know, right? I wonder if anyone noticed.
アキロゼ少し、ちょっと可愛くなってない？
Don't you think AkiRose has gotten a little cuter?
そう、メイクを今風にしてみたっていうか。
Yes, I tried doing my makeup in a more modern style.
髪の毛とかもオイルとかつけてツヤツヤにしてみたんだけど、どう？
I also put some oil in my hair to make it shiny. How is it?
どう？よく見て、よく見て。アップでちょっと。
How is it? Take a good look. Up close.
可愛い顔ぜひ！
Take a look at my cute face!
まあ、元から可愛いの知ってるんだけどね。
Well, I know I was cute to begin with.
スクショとかいっぱい撮って、ポストで呟いてね。ぜひ盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。
Take lots of screenshots and tweet them. I'd be happy if you'd help liven things up.
そして、まだまだ気を抜くなよ！
And, don't let your guard down yet!
この配信の後、メンバー限定でアフターライブもやる予定なので
After this stream, I'm planning an after-live for members only...
そちらもお楽しみに！メンバー登録するなら今だ今だ今だ！
...so look forward to that too! Join now, now, now!
そして、この配信のラストには...
And, at the end of this stream...
新曲をお披露目もあるから
I'll also be debuting a new song, so
最後まで楽しんでいってね！
please enjoy until the very end!
ということで、次の曲早速行っちゃいましょう！
So, let's get right into the next song!
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
青のすみか。
Ao no Sumika.
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seemed to go on forever
四つ並ぶ眼の前を遮るものは何もない
There's nothing blocking the view before our four eyes
アスファルト　蝉時雨を反射して
The asphalt reflects the chorus of cicadas
君という沈黙が聞こえなくなる
The silence that is you becomes inaudible
この日々が色褪せる
These days fade
僕と違う君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if I've come to know your scent, so different from mine
置き忘れてきた永遠の底に
At the bottom of the eternity we left behind
今でも青が棲んでいる
Even now, blue resides there
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, blue is clear
どんな祈りも言葉も近づけるのに届かなかった
No matter the prayers or words, they didn't reach despite bringing them close
まるで静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love
頬を伝った夏のような色のなか
In colors like the summer that ran down my cheeks
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥につかえてる
The words to curse you are forever stuck in the back of my throat
「また会えるよね」って
Saying, 'We'll meet again, right?'
声にならない声
A voice that won't become a sound
昼下がり　湿つく風の季節は
In the early afternoon, in the season of the clinging wind
想い馳せる　まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
Reflecting on the portraits of us, when we were still no one
何もかも分かち合えたはずだった
We should have been able to share everything
あの日から少しずつ　君と違う僕を呪いが生い茂って
From that day on, little by little, curses grew over the part of me that's different from you
君の笑顔と僕の憂いを見落としたこと悔やみ尽くして
Regretting to no end the fact that I overlooked your smile and my own sorrow
あだ花と咲いて散っていく君に
To you, who blooms like a sterile flower and then withers
さよなら
Goodbye
今でも青が棲んでいる
Even now, blue resides there
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, blue is clear
どんな祈りも言葉も近づけるのに届かなかった
No matter the prayers or words, they didn't reach despite bringing them close
まるで静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love
頬を伝った夏のような色のなか
In colors like the summer that ran down my cheeks
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥につかえてる
The words to curse you are forever stuck in the back of my throat
「また会えるよね」って
Saying, 'We'll meet again, right?'
声にならない声
A voice that won't become a sound
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように僕らは零れた
Like the grains of stars in an infinitely expanding galaxy, we spilled out
はーいみんなー！
Hi, everyone!
アロダー！
Alo-da!
ということで、本日、アキロゼ生誕祭
And so, the first guests for today's Aki Rose Birthday Festival
ゲスト最初に来ていただいたのは、柊派さん！
are Shuha-san...
そして、Bど君！
...and B-do-kun!
お誕生日おめでぴょー！
Happy Birthday-pyo!
ありがとうありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
いやーやったね。
Man, we did it.
すごいなんか、アイドルみたい。
Wow, it's like we're idols.
まるで。
Just like.
いやいやアイドルですけどね、元から。
No, no, I've been an idol from the start.
全然知らなくて。
I had no idea.
知らなかったね。
We didn't know, did we?
アイドル部分なんか見せずに来てたからね、今までね。
Well, I've been coming along without showing my idol side until now.
ギャングしか知らない。
We only know the gang side.
すごい変わった方だなと思ってたけど。
I thought you were a really strange person, but...
アイドルとは関係なく。
...unrelated to being an idol.
もしかしたら違ったのかも知れないね。
Maybe I was mistaken.
どうかな？
I wonder?
でもすごい。
But it's amazing.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
さすがね。
As expected.
3人で歌ってみたいなと思ってお願いして来てもらっちゃったんだけど。
I really wanted to sing with the three of us, so I asked and they came.
歌ってもらったんですけど...
Even though I had them sing...
でもね、歌は、まあ、いけると...
But you know, for the singing, well, I think we can...
それこそね、我々も頑張ってきましたよと。
Because of that, we've also worked hard.
今日はあるから。ありますよと。まあまあまあと思ってたんですけど。
Since we have this today. We do. Well, I thought it would be okay, but...
苦労したのはやっぱり踊りじゃないですか。
The hard part was definitely the dancing, wasn't it?
聞いてない！聞いてない！聞いてない！
I didn't hear about this! I didn't hear about this!
いや、踊らされるなんて聞いてない。聞いてません。聞いてないよ。
I didn't hear anything about being made to dance. I didn't hear it.
え、でもどう？ダンスレッスンもして、実際やってみてどうよ？
But how was it? After the dance lessons and actually trying it?
まあ… でもなんか、だってフォーメーションになってたじゃん、自然に。
Well... but the formation naturally came together, you know?
思ったより面白かったからな。まあまあ、結構楽しかったよね。
It was more interesting than I expected. It was quite fun, wasn't it?
結構楽しかったけど。あれ「1 2 3」ってやってたよね。
It was quite fun. We were doing the "1 2 3" count.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8、よいしょ！
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8, here we go!
もう頭の中でもずっとメトロノーム鳴ってんの。
A metronome has been ringing in my head the whole time.
カチ、カチ、カチ、カチ。
Tick, tick, tick, tick.
でもね、動けてて先生も褒めてたしね。
But you were moving well, and the teacher praised you!
いや、でも良かったけど、またやりたいかって言われるとちょっと…
It was good, but if you ask if I want to do it again, well...
あれ？そんな大変なんだ。いやもう…
Oh? Is it that tough? Yeah...
大変さはマジで身に沁みた。やっぱ踊ってる人の…
The difficulty really hit home. People who dance...
みんな、いやこれ、すごいんだなって。この人ね、本当にすごいよ。
...everyone, this is really amazing. This person is truly incredible.
いやー、そんな… 何も言えないよ。
Oh, no... I don't know what to say.
ほら！ほらもう見て、今の動き！見て今の動き！
Look! Look at that movement! Look at her move!
そんな、そんなクルッと回れないよ、簡単に。
You can't just spin like that easily!
一般人がやろうとしてみて… ここ、こんなん、こんなん、こんなんでしょ！こんなもんだよ、みんな。
If an ordinary person tried... it would be like this! This is how most people are.
その動きやめて！
Stop that movement!
すごいんだって！逆ギャップ出ちゃう！
I'm telling you, it's amazing! You're showing too much of a gap!
マジでその動きやめて。まあでも、見習わなきゃなと思いましたね。
Seriously, stop that movement. Well, I thought I should learn from you.
まあそうね。だってゲームばっかりやってるから、たまには動いた方がいいんじゃない？
True. Since you only play games, moving sometimes is good, right?
そう。こっから先は結構筋肉あるんだけどね。
Right. We have some muscle from here down, though.
そうだね、動かしてるね、毎日もうマウスブンブンですからね。
Yeah, we move them every day, flicking the mouse around.
ここでできない動きあるって言ってなかった？
Didn't you say there's a movement you can't do here?
えっとね、何だっけな。ピンと手を伸ばせない。これが…
Let's see... what was it? Not being able to stretch the arm straight.
ほら！これができないって。
Look! See? He can't do this.
まあ、伸ばしにくいっすけど。これFPS筋のあれっすよ。
Well, it's hard to stretch. It's because of the FPS muscles.
FPS筋がああだこうだ… 手首がね、硬い。
FPS muscles this and that... his wrists are stiff.
手首が硬いっすね。俺はフニャフニャ。
My wrists are stiff. Mine are floppy.
まあ、なんかレイドくんフニャフニャっす。
Yeah, somehow Reid-kun is all floppy.
まだじゃあFPS筋育ってない。俺、結構やってるけど…
Then your FPS muscles aren't developed yet. I play quite a bit, though...
そうだよね。いやでも、これもね、全部VCRのGTA…
I know. But this is all thanks to VCR GTA...
そうね。2ですかね。あの、前々回かな。
Right. Season 2? The one before last?
前々回だ。そう聞くとめっちゃ尊みある。
The one before last. It feels really precious when you put it like that.
あったね。でも実は1年ちょっと。なんだかんだ1年ちょっと。
It does. But it's actually only been a little over a year.
1年ちょっと。そうだよね。あの時に、まあね。
A little over a year. That's right. Back then...
あれ？
Huh?
あ、なんか、あれ？なんか聞こえる？何ですかこれ？
Oh, wait. Can you hear something? What is this?
おめでとう！！うぉおおおおお！！
CONGRATULATIONS!! WHOOOOOO!!
わあ！みんな！うぉお！嬉しい！ありがとうありがとう！
Wow! Everyone! Oh! I'm so happy! Thank you, thank you!
おいおいおい！いっぱい来たね！めちゃくちゃいいじゃん。
Whoa, whoa! So many people came! This is awesome.
多いな。多いね。
There's a lot of us. Quite a few.
ということで、じゃあネオポリスのみんな、大集合です！やったー！
So, the Neopolis group is all here! Yay!
やったー！お願いしまーす！
Yay! Nice to be here!
じゃあ、自己紹介とさせていただきますか？そうですね。お願いします。
Shall we do some self-introductions? Yes, please go ahead.
じゃあ、エビさんから！
Then, starting with Ebi-san!
あ、はい、わかりました。こんぱんエビ！
Ah, okay, got it. Kon-ban-Ebi!
にじさんじ所属バーチャルライバー、エクス・アルビオでーす。
I'm Ex-Albio, a Virtual Liver from Nijisanji.
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
はい、ありがとう！じゃ次、ランちゃん！
Yes, thank you! Next, Lan-chan!
あ、どうもこんばんは！火之駒ランです！
Ah, hello, good evening! I'm Hinokoma Lan!
えー、何もしてんまーす！よろしくお願いします！
I'm not doing anything special! Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！変わったね。じゃ次、トトさん！
Yay! You've changed! Next, Toto-san!
はい、どこにも所属してない、ととみっくすです。
Yes, I'm Totomix, not affiliated with anyone.
お願いします！所属あるんですか、今年は。
Nice to meet you! Are you affiliated this year?
どこにも所属してません。今年こそは！今年こそはね。まあどこかに。
I'm not affiliated anywhere. This year for sure! This year, right? Somewhere...
ホロライブでお待ちしてます。
We're waiting for you at Hololive.
え、マジで？一番違うやろ、俺。いいなー。じゃ次、マザーちゃん！
Wait, seriously? I'd be the most out of place! Nice. Next, Mother-chan!
はい、マザーです。よろしくお願いします！おめでとう。
Yes, I'm Mother. Nice to meet you! Congratulations.
唯一の実写、マザー！おー、かっけー！
The only one in real life, Mother! Oh, so cool!
ね、らしいね。なんかどうなってんだよ、ととみっくす。恥ずかしいだろ、なんか逆に俺が。
Yeah, it seems so. What's going on, Totomix? It's kind of embarrassing for me instead.
すいません、なんか。失礼します。ありがとね。次、琥珀ちゃん！
Sorry about that. My apologies. Thank you. Next, Kohaku-chan!
はい！琥珀！Sony Music VEE所属の、
Yes! Kohaku! From Sony Music VEE,
節子琥珀です。ヤッホー！
I'm Setsuko Kohaku. Yahoo!
ヤッホーイ！うぇーい！続いて、トモさん！
Yahoo! Yay! Next, Tomo-san!
はい、赤髪のともです。えー、おめでとうございます！
Yes, I'm Akagami no Tomo. Congratulations!
え、なんか硬い！もっと崩していいのに。
Oh, you're so stiff! You can just relax!
ともさんだけVTRじゃないよね、これ。いるよね。いたいたいた！よかった。
Tomo-san isn't a VTR, right? He's actually there. There he is! Good.
いや、準備されてるかもしれない、今の。ポチ、ポチッと。トモさんポチ。あ、そしてねこたちゅ！
Actually, he might be prepared. Pressing the button. Tomo-button. Oh, and Nekotachi!
こんぱんエビ！ぶいすぽの猫汰つなでーす。
Kon-ban-Ebi! I'm Nekota Tsuna from VSPO!
なんで？なんで「こんぱんエビ」？エビ要素ないだろ、猫汰に！
Why? Why "Kon-ban-Ebi"? There's no Ebi element in Nekota!
いや、1回言いたかった。言ってみたかった。わかるよその気持ち。
I just wanted to say it once. I wanted to try it. I know how you feel.
ねこたすなっくす！
Nekota-snax!
VCRということで...
Because of VCR...
みんな ありがとう 来てくれて！
Thank you everyone for coming!
こないだね あのハードコアのマイクラもやったりとか
The other day, we also played hardcore Minecraft...
ありましたね
We sure did.
あったね
Yeah.
あらら どっせい居なくなったけどな
Oh, although Dossei disappeared.
無事にクリアしましたしね 我々は
But we cleared it safely.
我々はね
We did.
いや 本当すごかった マジですごかった
No, it was really amazing, seriously amazing.
頑張ってたよね あれね
You worked hard on that.
最後感動したよね マジで
The ending was really touching.
そうだよねー かなたん
Isn't that right, Kanatan?
もう ドキドキハラハラ
I was so nervous.
大冒険ね
A grand adventure.
すごかったんだから
Because it was truly amazing.
今度は二人でやるんでしょ？
Next time, you two will do it together?
海馬ハードコア
Kaiba hardcore.
いいね
Nice.
みんなで邪魔しに行こう
Let's all go and get in their way.
邪魔しに...
To mess with...
あとはね VCRのGTA 3でも ちょっとあったりとか
And then, there was also a bit of VCR GTA 3...
あったねー
That's true.
そうだよね みんなやったねー
Right, everyone played it.
毎度 ネオポリスの集まりになると 欠席者がちょっといるらしいけど
Every time the Neopolis crew gathers, there are always some missing.
いやね マジでよかったわー
Seriously, it was great.
あれ 全員集まらなかったっけ？
Wait, didn't everyone gather then?
無事 全員集まったのどうした？
How did everyone manage to gather?
ねぇ かなたんどうした？ 欠席したよね？
Hey, Kanatan, what happened? You were absent, right?
しかたないだろ！
I couldn't help it!
え、私 あの時最後の方までソロで...
I was playing solo until the end...
映画出てた 映画出てた
You were in a movie! You were in a movie!
あ、確かに 映画出てた 映画出てた
Ah, that's right. You were in a movie.
堂々としろ！ 私みたいに堂々としろ！
Be confident! Stand tall like me!
自分では見られなかったっていう...
I couldn't see it for myself...
アーカイブで... アーカイブで見に行ってください
In the archives... Please go watch the archives.
ちょっと時間がね 合わなかった
The timing just didn't work out.
まあまあまあ
Well, well.
ARKとかね やってみたりとか しつつあるんですけど
We've also been doing things like ARK...
はい
Yes.
まあ まだみんなで 今度は また全員揃ってね
Well, next time, let's all get together again.
次こそ 歌おう
Let's definitely sing next time.
今日 3人で歌ったし
Since three of us sang today.
呼んでくださいよ！
Please invite us!
全員で歌うってこと？
You mean everyone singing together?
10人で歌ってみようよっていう話をしてる
We're talking about all ten of us singing together.
しようよ
Let's do it.
だって今回ね アキさんが言うから 我々も... まぁ ポポトレイドくんとか特に ダンスもしたことない中 頑張ってレッスンして
Because Aki-san asked, we... well, especially Popo Trade-kun, even though he's never danced before, he worked hard in lessons.
そうだよ 踊ったんだよ
That's right. He actually danced.
ととさんは何で踊ってないの？ これ
Why isn't Toto-san dancing?
え、アトミックス
Wait, Atomics?
何で踊ってないの？
Why aren't you dancing?
い、いいから... まぁ 呼んでもらったら やりますが
I-It's fine... Well, if I'm invited, I'll do it.
え、ととさん やるの！？
What, Toto-san, you'll do it!?
現地です。本当に。
On-site. Seriously.
ちょっとずつ増やしていこう。じゃあ次 ととさん入れて4人で。
Let's increase the number gradually. Next time, let's have four people including Toto-san.
こっち側じゃなくて そっち側に居るから 次は。
I'll be on that side next time, not this side.
そうだよねー おお！ 言った言った言った！
That's right! Oh! He said it! He said it!
大変だったよ...
It was really tough...
そうだよね レッスン頑張ってくれたんだよね
That's right, you worked really hard in lessons.
でもね 楽しかったですしね 本当ね
But it was really fun, honestly.
ととさんがやってるの めっちゃおもろい
Seeing Toto-san do it is hilarious.
見たいね。おもろいって言っちゃった。めっちゃ見たい。キレッキレのやつ見たい。
I want to see it. I said it's funny, but I really want to see it. I want to see a sharp performance.
ととさん用を
One for Toto-san.
まじか。まぁまぁといったところで...
Seriously. Well then...
お時間が 迫ってるということで
Time is running out...
えー 早い！
Oh, already!?
10人もいるのにねー
Even though there are ten of us here.
たくさん喋りたいと思うんですけど
I'd love to talk more, but...
まあ最後に ちょっともう一回 みんなで ボスをお祝いしようかなということで
So, let's all celebrate the boss one last time together.
いいですか？
Are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ せーの！
All right, one, two...!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
またやろうねー
Let's do this again!
やるぞー！ おめでとう！
We will! Congratulations!
ありがとう！ バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
まるで御伽の話
Just like a fairy tale,
終わり迎えた証
A sign that it has reached its end.
長すぎる旅路から
From a journey that was far too long,
切り出した一節
A passage carved out.
それはかつてこの地に
It was once in this land,
影を落とした悪を
The evil that cast a shadow,
討ち取りし勇者との
Defeated by the hero.
勇者
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Hero
Lyrics/Composition: Ayase
短い旅の記憶
Memories of that short journey.
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story ends, and the hero goes to sleep.
穏やかな日常を この地に残して
Leaving behind a peaceful daily life in this land.
時の流れは無情に 人を忘れさせる
The passage of time heartlessly makes people forget.
そこに生きた軌跡も 錆び付いていく
The traces of life there also begin to rust.
それでも君の 言葉も願いも勇気も
Yet even now, your words, your wishes, your courage,
今も確かに私の中で 生きてる
They certainly still live on within me.
同じ途を選んだ それだけだったはずなのに
I only chose the same path, that was all it should have been,
いつの間にかどうして 頬を伝う涙
Yet before I knew it, why are tears streaming down my cheeks?
勇者
Brave
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと
I want to know more about the reason
知りたいんだ 今更だって
for the tears running down your cheeks, even now.
共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
If I trace the journey we walked together,
そこに君はいなくとも
even if you're not there,
きっと見つけられる
I'm sure I can find it.
物語は続く
The story continues,
独りの旅へと立つ
as I set out on a journey alone.
立ち寄る街で出会う人の記憶の中に残る君は
In the memories of people I meet in the towns I visit, you remain,
相も変わらずお人好しで格好つけてばかりだね
as kind-hearted and pretentious as ever.
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは勝ち取った平和の証
The symbols built here and there are proof of the peace we won.
それら眺めていつか私が独りにならないように
So that I won't be alone when I look at them someday,
あの旅を思い出せるように残された目印
they are markers left behind so I can remember that journey.
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale,
終わり迎えた証
a sign that it's come to an end.
私を変えた出会い
The encounter that changed me,
100年も続く旅路
a journey that will last for a hundred years.
君の勇気をいつか風が攫って
Someday, the wind will carry away your courage,
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
and even if it vanishes from everyone's memory,
私が未来に連れていくから
I will carry it into the future.
君の手を取ったあの日全て始まった
Everything started that day I took your hand.
くだらなくて思わずふっと笑ってしまうような
Those trivial, mundane moments that make me
ありふれた時間が今も眩しい
chuckle suddenly are still dazzling today.
知りたいんだ 今更だって
I want to know, even now,
振り返るとそこにはいつでも
because whenever I look back, you are always there,
優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
smiling gently at me.
新たな旅の始まりは
The start of a new journey
君が守り抜いたこの地に
is here in this land that you protected,
芽吹いた命と共に
together with the life that has begun to bud.
はーい！見えてるみんな？アローダー！
Hi! Can everyone see me? Aloda!
今日はね、色んなゲストも来てくれたりお話できたりして、めちゃくちゃ楽しいし、
Today, I've had various guests come and talk to me, and it's been so much fun,
生誕祭ライブ最高！
and this birthday celebration live is the best!
みんなありがとうー！
Thank you, everyone!
あ、なんか聞こえる。聞こえる気がする。
Oh, I hear something. I think I hear something.
なんか...なんだ？
What... what is it?
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy birthday!
おめでとー！
え、それまさか打ち合わせ済み？それ。
Wait, was that rehearsed? That.
いや、心こもってるから。
No, it's from the heart.
心こもってる？本当？
From the heart? Really?
「せーの」で行こうって言って。
We said, "Let's go on three."
いや、この声は、もしかして、
Wait, these voices, could it be...
V最のメンバー、プレデターと一緒の、みんな！？
The V-Saikyo members, everyone from Predator!?
バレちまったか。
You caught us.
バレバレだよ！ということで、じゃあ改めて自己紹介お願いします。
It was so obvious! So, let's have everyone introduce themselves again.
じゃあ、ディトちゃん！
Okay, Dito!
えーと、はい。REJECT所属のDitoと申します。よろしくお願いします。
Um, yes. I'm Dito from REJECT. Nice to meet you.
次、メイカちゃん！
Next, Meika!
歌衣メイカです！よろしくお願いします！
I'm Utai Meika! Nice to meet you!
そして、ナッチさん！
And, Nacchi-san!
ナッチです。よろしくお願いします。
I'm Nacchi. Nice to meet you.
緊張してる？
Are you nervous?
めちゃくちゃ緊張してる。
I'm super nervous.
緊張しないでー。こんなデカい舞台ね。
Don't be nervous! On such a big stage.
そうだよね。
That's true.
そして、向井浩二！
And, Mukai Kouji!
はい、向井浩二です。お願いします。おめでとうございます！
Yes, I'm Mukai Kouji. Nice to meet you. Congratulations!
時間の許す限り話すぞ。
I'm going to talk as much as time allows.
いや、いいよいいよ。
No, go for it.
このメンバーということで、プレデターと一緒のメンツを今日は
Since it's this group, I reached out to the members from Predator
お声がけさせていただきまして、来ていただきました。ありがとうね、みんな。
to come here today. Thank you for coming, everyone.
こちらこそありがとうございます。呼んでいただいて。
Thank you so much for inviting us.
我々みたいなのが、この場に上がってもうて。
People like us getting to be on this stage.
緊張しなくていいから！
You don't have to be nervous!
ちょっと待って、ナッチさ、ちっちゃいな。
Wait a second, Nacchi, you're tiny.
ちっちゃいね。
I am small.
我々といえば、大会ありましたね。
Speaking of us, there was that tournament.
そうだよ。なんかでも、もう懐かしいというか、1年もまだ経ってないけどね。
That's right. It feels nostalgic, even though it hasn't even been a year yet.
あ、でも半年くらいか、あれも。
Oh, but it's been about half a year since then.
あ、そう！
Oh, right!
だいぶ経ってる。全然集まんねーじゃねーか俺たち。
Quite a while. We haven't gathered at all, have we?
そうだよ。なんであれっきりなんだ。
True. Why has it been only that once?
どうして。誕生日に逆に呼べて、ありがとうね。
Why? Anyway, thank you for letting me invite you for my birthday.
ディトちゃんとはね、ちょこちょこ同じチームになったり、イベント出たり、
With Dito-chan, we've been on the same team a few times, appeared at events,
コラボしたりしてるんだけど。
and done collaborations.
あれでしょ？こはくちゃんとやってたやつでしょ？
That was the one you were doing with Kohaku-chan, right?
あ、そうそうそう。
Oh, yeah, yeah.
俺見て嫉妬コメ打つか悩んでやめたもん。
I watched that and debated whether to post a jealous comment.
それはやってよ！「俺のこと置いていくんだ」っつって。
You should've done it! Like, "You're leaving me behind!"
そういうのがやっぱ可愛いってなるから
Because that's what makes people think "cute."
やってほしい
I want you to do it.
俺は可愛い売りしてねえから
I'm not selling "cute" here.
そっか男気の方だった
Right, it was the "manly" side.
男だからね そうそう
I'm a man, after all. Right, right.
でもアキロゼがね 声かけなくても
But even if I don't call out...
遊んでくれたら嬉しいなと思うんだけど
I'd be happy if you played with me.
何だったらじゃあ一緒に遊んでくれる？今後なんか一緒にね
So, what should we play together? In the future, you know.
マリカ？
Mario Kart?
あー、いい！ マリカ？
Ah, that's good! Mario Kart?
マリオカートありっすね。相当下手にするけど。
Mario Kart is an option. Though I'm quite bad at it.
みんなでできる
Everyone can play.
え、じゃあみけちゃんが強いんだ
Eh, so Mike-chan is strong.
めっちゃ強いよ。
I'm super strong.
でも俺も一個もっと前の作品だけど日本代表だったよ。
But I was also a Japan representative, although for an earlier title.
え、やばい！ 強いの出てきた！
Wait, no way! Someone strong appeared!
余裕じゃない？
Isn't it a breeze then?
みけちゃんの今の強者感がすごい。
The strong-guy aura Mike-chan has now is amazing.
でも本当に強い男はそんな強く言わないんだ。
But a truly strong man doesn't brag like that.
うーん。
Hmm.
日本代表級はまずいか、ちょっと。
Maybe "Japan representative level" is a bit much.
カートの方は弱いです。バイクの方は強いですけど。
I'm weak with karts. But I'm strong with bikes.
あ、じゃあバイク縛り。
Ah, then let's do a bike-only rule.
バイク縛りで。
Bike-only then.
え、マジなんだ。すごいね。
Wait, you're serious? That's amazing.
じゃあマリカコラボやるか。
Then shall we do a Mario Kart collab?
やったっていい。
I'm down for it.
じゃあ今後もね ぜひ遊んでもらえたら嬉しいなと思って
I'd be happy if we could play together in the future.
アキロゼから誘えば みんなからもぜひ気軽にね
If I invite you, or if you guys want to suggest something...
もちろんなっちさんからも。
Of course, from Nacchi-san as well.
最近なんか全然ARKに来ない。ひどい。
Lately, he hasn't been coming to ARK at all. It's terrible.
絶対来ない。ひどい。
He never comes. How cruel.
ARKだっていうのは分かってる。
I know it's ARK.
じゃあARKやりましょう。
Then let's play ARK.
ARKやりたいね。
I want to play ARK.
普通に好きなんだよね。
I actually quite like it.
あ、本当。
Oh, really?
じゃあ遊べる人が増えて嬉しい。ARK友達にもなれる。
Then I'm glad more people can play. We can be ARK friends too.
今後もいろいろやりましょう。
Let's do various things in the future.
今日は忙しい中来てくれてありがとうね。
Thank you for coming today despite being busy.
絶対優勝しようね。
Let's definitely win.
絶対優勝しようね、マジで。
Let's definitely win, for real.
カスタム1位取ったからね、俺たち。
We took 1st place in the custom match, after all.
本番でも取るぞ！
Let's take it in the real thing too!
またねー！
See you later!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
燃いら万象 見会えど ピー
Moira-banjuu, Mikadopi...
溶けてゆく ルルルル
Melting away, luruluru.
清楚装ってる 泥棒猫の罠は誘い
Dressed in purity, the stray cat's trap invites.
Bam bam with us...
誰も見付けないだろ 正解と同じでしょ
No one will find it, just like the right answer.
Bam bam with us...
甘い甘い 腐食的な愛ソング 駆け引きなんて響かない
A sweet, sweet corrosive love song, tactics don't resonate.
私欲望のまま身体だけだから
Because I'm just a body following desire.
二人しか知らないこのロマンス 罪なジュネラス won't be paradise
A romance only the two of us know, sinful and generous, won't be paradise.
麻痺するな愛にもっと変化して
Don't let it numb, transform more into love.
貯めてよ 危険な火遊びを
Gather it up, this dangerous play with fire.
飲み込んで 牙剥いて
Swallow it down, bare your fangs.
宵限りファンタジア
An evening-only fantasia.
さあ踊って その指が刺せ satisfaction
Now dance, let those fingers point to satisfaction.
あとは落日の間 転げて甘々底まで
After that, in the sunset's gap, rolling down to the sweet bottom.
Down low low
瞑想の意識性 扉を射込んで
Meditative consciousness, shooting through the door.
零れてる吐息が 止まない刺激が
Overflowing sighs, an unceasing stimulation.
人のモノだろうが
Even if it belongs to someone else.
燃いら万象 見会えど ピー
Moira-banjuu, Mikadopi...
溶けてゆく ルルルル
Melting away, luruluru.
いたずらままごと そんな言葉じゃずっとぬるい
Playful house-acting, such words are far too lukewarm.
Bam bam with us...
一瞬の儚い夢こそ グサって残るでしょ
Fleeting dreams of a moment are the ones that pierce and remain.
Bam bam with us...
あなたと私で何がしたい どんな計算だって当てにしない
What do you want to do with me? I won't rely on any calculations.
目と袖で答え書き和えるから
Through eyes and sleeves, we'll write our answer together.
後ろ手で鍵をかけてランデヴー 優しもの狙って綻ぶ
Locking the door behind us, a rendezvous targeting something gentle as it unravels.
冷え付いたなら もっと変化して
If it's grown cold, then transform even more.
ひめてよ 醜い火遊びを
Hide it away, this ugly play with fire.
モラルも 理性も おふざけりの獣に
Moral and reason, to a playful beast.
超越制のヒプノシス
A transcendental hypnosis.
絡めて 楽にして ここから先は satisfaction
Entwine it, make it easy, from here on is satisfaction.
アイダをとっぱらって
Let's break the distance between us
もういらないから
Because I don't need it anymore
ポンコツの刃(ハ)ぬ
Drawing a useless blade
Down Low Low Low Low
わがまま こじらせ
Complicating my selfishness
騙し騙されるはず
Tricking and being tricked
あやまちは No return
The mistake is a point of no return
虜に染めるカラー
Colors that dye you as a captive
もう戻れないなら
If you can't go back anymore
ただ奪い去るだけ
I'll just take it all away
さあ 塞いで
Now, seal it up
ウイスキーの香りの口づけで
With a kiss that smells like whiskey
今宵はあなたと獲物
Tonight, you and the prey
仕留めて火をつけて
Take it down and set it on fire
咎めてよ 馬鹿げた火遊びを
Reproach me for this foolish fire play
孤独が 鼓動が ここじゃやめられないじゃん
Loneliness and heartbeats, I can't stop it here, right?
Woah
背徳のトラジェディ
A tragedy of immorality
誰かさんとの約束ごと
A promise made to someone
ただ奪い去るだけ
Just taking it all away
求めてよ 危険な火遊びを
Seek it, this dangerous fire play
甘えて 悶えて 裸に牙を剥いて
Being spoiled, writhing, showing fangs to the bare skin
今宵限りのファンタジー
A fantasy for tonight only
待ってないで さあ踊って その指焦がして ビビディバビディバップ
Don't wait, now dance, burn those fingers, Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Bop
あとはなすがまま
Leave the rest as it is
焦げちままさ
Just let it burn away
地獄の底まで
To the very depths of hell
Down Low Low Low Low
冷めた意識さえ 宙へ飛び込んで
Even cold consciousness dives into the air
こぼれてる吐息が
Overflowing sighs
止まない刺激が
Unending stimulation
人のモノだろうが
Even if it belongs to someone else
ただ奪い去るだけ
Just taking it all away
真夜中 密会のアピール
A midnight secret meeting appeal
溶けていく ルール
Melting rules
真夜中 密会のアピール
A midnight secret meeting appeal
溶けていく ルール
Melting rules
イエーイ！
Yay!
ということで、ちくまろのみんなです！
And so, here is everyone from Chiku-Maro!
イエーイ！
Yay!
来たー！お邪魔します！
We're here! Thanks for having us!
いや、なんか嬉しい。ここに来てくれて、本当に嬉しいなぁ。
Wow, I'm so happy. I'm really glad you guys could come here.
いやぁ、ありがとうございます。こんな大きなライブに呼んでいただいて。
No, thank you. Thank you for inviting us to such a big live.
いやでも、マジで広いんだね。すっげー！
But seriously, it's really spacious. Amazing!
ねえ、マジで広い！
Yeah, it's really huge!
本当？
Really?
いやでも、今日はね、アキロゼの生誕祭にわざわざ来てくれて、本当にありがとう。
But really, thank you so much for coming all this way for Aki-Rose's birthday celebration today.
いやいや、こちらこそ！
No, the pleasure is ours!
おめでとう！誕生日おめでとう！めでたい！
Happy Birthday! Congratulations! Such a happy occasion!
ありがと。いつかやってみたかったことだから、一つ願いが叶ったも同然なんだ。
Thank you. This is something I've always wanted to do, so it's like a dream has come true.
おおー！よかったー！嬉しい！
Oh! That's great! So happy for you!
ということで、じゃあせっかくなんでね、ここで自己紹介、しときますかね？
So, since we're all here, should we do some self-introductions?
はい！
Sure!
じゃあ、ひまちゃんからお願いします！
Alright, Himari-chan, you first please!
はい！皆さんどうも、おはガオー、おはガオー、おはガオーたまで、本間ひまりが、ぽんぷたー、本間ひまりでーす！
Hi! Everyone! Oha-gao, oha-gao, oha-goatama! I'm Honma Himari! Pumptam! Honma Himari-desu!
本物だー！ひまちゃん！こんひまー！
It's the real one! Himari-chan! Kon-hima!
めっちゃ元気。感動した、なんか。
She's so energetic. I'm actually moved somehow.
本物だって言ったよ、今。
She just said 'It's the real one'.
まあ、こっちからしても本物だって感じだけどね。
Well, it feels like the real thing from my side too.
そっかそっか、そうだよね。
I see, I see, you're right.
じゃあ、続いてべにちゃんお願いします。
Next up, Beni-chan, please.
はい皆さん、えー、おはセクシー、こんセクシー。あ、どうも、ぶいすぽのセクシー担当、八雲べにです。どうも。
Hi everyone. Um, Oha-sexy, Kon-sexy. Ah, hello, I'm Yakumo Beni, the one in charge of sexiness in V-SPO. Hello.
色気がやべー！
Her sexiness is insane!
今、作りました。
I just made that up.
いや、そんな挨拶いらないくらい声セクシーだけどね。
No, your voice is sexy enough without needing an intro like that.
お、それ背負っていけんの？この一年。
Oh, can you carry that burden for the next year?
いや、ちょっとこのメンツの前では、ひまちゃんの前でしか言えない、これ。
No, I can only say this in front of Himari-chan, not in front of this group.
いやいや、セクシー！
No, no, it's sexy!
ちょっとアキちゃんとチョコ先生の前では、こんセクシーなんて言えない。
I can't say 'Kon-sexy' in front of Aki-chan and Choco-sensei.
ひまもセクシー担当でやってるんだから。
I'm also acting as the sexy representative!
嘘をつけ！どこに誰がセクシー担当なんだよ！
Liar! Who on earth is the sexy representative?!
ひまはセクシー！
Himari is sexy!
いやいや、じゃあまあ、ホロのセクシー担当にもお願いしますか。チョコ先、お願いします。
Well then, let's ask Hololive's sexy representative as well. Choco-sensei, please.
え、じゃあ行っちゃおうかな。
Eh, then should I go for it?
おお！やばい！空気変わる！
Oh! This is bad! The atmosphere is changing!
チョコ... ホロライブセクシー担当、癒月チョコです。
Choco... I'm Yuzuki Choco, Hololive's sexy representative.
何それ！チョコ先生！何今のチョコ！
What was that?! Choco-sensei! What was that 'Choco' just now?!
それはもうご想像にお任せします。お願いします。
I'll leave that to your imagination. Thank you.
うわー。待って、時の流れが今5倍くらいゆっくりしてた。
Wow. Wait, time was moving about five times slower just now.
ひまちゃん、これがセクシー担当だよ。
Hima-chan, this is what the sexy role looks like.
なるほどね！
I see!
ひまわりです〜！
It's Himawari~!
いいねいいね。
Nice, nice.
いやでもさ、みんなね、この「ちくまのの」の4人はさ、
But you know, the four of us in 'Chikumanono'...
セクシー担当ってま、前のApexかな？コラボの時に言ってたからね。
we were called the 'sexy ones' back in that Apex collab, right?
今日はちょっとセクシーな曲を4人でやってみたいなと思って、この曲にしたの。
So I thought I'd like the four of us to try a sexy song today, which is why I chose this one.
あ、なるほどね！確かに！
Oh, I see! Definitely!
めっちゃセクシー！いや、ダンスがね、めっちゃセクシーだったくないですか？
So sexy! I mean, wasn't the dance super sexy?
めっちゃセクシーだった！
It was super sexy!
でしょ？
Right?
いやね〜めちゃめちゃ良かった。
Yeah, it was really great.
振り付け見た時、これいけるかなって思ったけど...
When I first saw the choreography, I wondered if we could pull it off, but...
めっちゃ良かった。
It was great.
いやチョコ先もいつも以上に腰くねくねさせちゃったら？
And Choco-sen, didn't you sway your hips even more than usual?
くねくね〜
Wiggle wiggle~
させましたね、だいぶ。
You really did, quite a bit.
ひまちゃんもセクシーに磨きがかかって。
And Hima-chan, you've really polished your sexiness too.
いや本当だよ！セクシーすぎてやばい！
I know, right! It's so sexy it's crazy!
ひまわりもね、セクシーすぎて爆発しちゃうかもしれないから！
I might even explode from being too sexy!
どこが？
In what way?
どこだろう？
I wonder where?
爆発するとこも是非見せてもらいたいなと思うんですけど。
I'd definitely like to see you explode then.
ま、今年もね、「ちくまのの」4人でなんか色々楽しいこととか、
Anyway, I hope we can do lots of fun things—
セクシーなこととか、できたら嬉しいなと思ってますので。
and sexy things—as the four of us in 'Chikumanono' again this year.
セクシーなこと？
Sexy things?
いやそれはちょっと言えない...
Well, I can't really say...
言えないの？アキちゃんが言うとなんかもっと卑猥に聞こえるんだけど！
You can't? When Aki-chan says it, it sounds even more lewd!
いやじゃあ、ローション相撲しましょうか。
Well then, shall we do lotion wrestling?
ローション相撲！？やべやばい！
Lotion wrestling!? Oh no!
このにじさんじさん、お願いします。
Nijisanji, if you please.
はーい、使いまーす！
Okay, I'll do it!
はい、ということでひまちゃん、べにちゃん、チョコ先、ありがとね！
All right, so Hima-chan, Beni-chan, Choco-sen, thank you so much!
ありがとー！お疲れ様でした！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Good work! Bye-bye!
ふぅ〜...いや〜今日の誕生日はめちゃくちゃすごいな。
Phew... wow, today's birthday celebration is truly amazing.
こんなにね、色んなゲストの人が来てくれて、たくさんお話ししたり、歌ったり踊ったりして楽しいな〜。
With so many guests coming over, talking, singing, and dancing... it's so much fun.
アキロゼさーん！
Aki-roze-san!
お？お？もしカして、その声は...
Oh? Oh? Could it be, that voice is...
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
お〜、村長！お村長だ！
Oh, Village Chief! It's the Village Chief!
アキロゼさん、おめでとうございます。
Aki-roze-san, happy birthday.
ありがと村長！え、来てくれたの？あれ、村長一人で来てくれたの、もしカして？
Thank you, Chief! Oh, you came? Wait, did you come alone, by any chance?
いやいや、まさか。みんないますよ。
No, no, of course not. Everyone is here.
もしかして...？
Could it be...?
おめでとー！おめでとー！
Happy Birthday! Congratulations!
え〜、ガエル村のみんなだ！わざわざみんな来てくれたんだ！
Oh, it's everyone from Guile Village! You all came all this way!
来たよー！また来たよ！
We're here! We're back!
二度目ましてもいるよね？
There are some 'nice to meet you for the second time' people here too, right?
また来ちゃった。
I'm back again.
また来てくれたんだ。待ってた待ってた！
You came back. I was waiting, I was waiting!
なんかまた増えちゃってる人もいるけど。
It looks like your numbers have grown again.
ということでね、本日ガエル村のみんなが来てくれました〜！
And so, everyone from Guile Village has joined us today!
おめでとー！おめでとー！
Happy Birthday! Congratulations!
せっかくなんでね、自己紹介タイムさせていただきまスカね。
Since you're all here, why don't we have some self-introductions?
え、マジかよ！気合入れて！
Wait, for real!? Put your back into it!
じゃあ、なんかアキロゼのパーカー着てくれてる村長！
First, the Chief, who's wearing an Aki-roze hoodie!
ありがとうございます。自己紹介お願いします。
Thank you very much. Please introduce yourself.
自己紹介します。大瞬感ソル熊本所属のひぐちです。
I'll introduce myself. I'm Higuchi, from Daishunkan Solu Kumamoto.
普段ね、ま、薬吐いたプレイして、アキロゼさんのガイルを、あの、鍛えてる村長と呼ばれている者です。よろしくお願いします。
I'm the one called 'Village Chief' who usually trains Aki-roze-san's Guile. Nice to meet you.
丁寧な！よっ村長！
How polite! All hail the Chief!
続いて、ドンさん！
Next up, Don-san!
あ、えー、三人グループで活動しております、三人称のドンピシャと申します。
Ah, hello. I'm Donpisha from the three-man group Sanninsho.
ガエル村では副村長と呼ばれておりまして、アキさんのコーチなんぞもしておりますね。
In Guile Village, I'm called the Vice Chief, and I also act as Aki-san's coach.
いつもありがと！よろしくお願いします。
Thank you as always! Nice to meet you.
続いてどうしようかな...リモーネ先生！
Next, who should it be... Rimone-sensei!
俺！？俺でここで！？準備してなかったなあ。
Me!? Me, here and now!? I wasn't prepared.
えーと、そうすね。結構アキロゼさんと最近色々お話しさせていただいたりして...
Well, let's see. I've been talking with Aki-roze-san quite a bit lately...
チーム友達でもね。
Also in Team Tomodachi.
そうですね。あの、ちょっとガイルじゃアキ最近ちょっと強く...アキ上手になってるってこと...
That's right. Regarding her Guile, Aki has been getting stronger lately... Aki is getting better...
まあまあ、でも一応弾も、ガイルも弾も、弾も寝てるけど。
Well, well, but the projectiles... Guile's projectiles... she's still sleeping on the projectiles.
アキもさ、あ、
Aki also, ah—
リモーネ先生と申します。よろしくお願いします。
I'm Limone Sensei. Nice to meet you.
はい、ありがとう！お願いします！
Yes, thank you! Nice to meet you!
じゃあ続いて、カズヨ！
Okay, next up, Kazuyo!
はい。あ、にじさんじ所属の玉餅カズヨです。
Yes. Ah, I'm Tamamochi Kazuyo from Nijisanji.
アキロゼさんとは、あの、同じモダンガイル使いだったということで...
Since Aki-rose and I are both Modern Guile users...
そうそう！
Right, right!
あの、モダンガイルの辛いところを唯一共有できる仲間だと思っております。
I consider her the only comrade I can share the struggles of using Modern Guile with.
そうなんだよー！すごい心強かったー。
Exactly! It was so reassuring.
辛い部分なんだｗ
The "struggles" part, huh? lol
バタバタしてる、共感力って大事だからね。
Flailing around... empathy is important, after all.
ありがとうございまーす。はい！
Thank you very much. Yes!
じゃあ続いて、レンくん！
Okay, next, Len-kun!
はい！ぶいすぽっ！所属、JP使い、如月レンです。よろしくお願いします。
Yes! I'm Kisaragi Len from Vspo!, a JP user. Nice to meet you.
誕生日おめでとう、アキロゼさん！
Happy Birthday, Aki-rose!
ありがとう！レンくんとはさ、まだゆっくりコラボできてない気がするんだよね。
Thank you! I feel like I haven't had a chance to collab with you properly yet.
そう、そう。雑談コラボとかいっそやろう、みたいな話ししたよね？
Right. We talked about just doing a chatting collab or something, didn't we?
したしたした！アリだよね。
We did, we did! That would be great.
やっぱあれだよね。電流でスマブラの時だけ？
Actually, was it only during that electric shock Smash Bros event?
あ、そうかも！あの時だけなんだｗ
Oh, maybe! Only then? lol
でも、なんかね、ちゃんと組んだのはあの時ぐらいかも、わりと。
But, you know, that might be the only time we really teamed up.
そうだよね！じゃあ今年はやろう！絶対に。
True! So let's do it this year! Definitely.
やろう。
Let's.
まああの時もね、我々結託しておりましたから。
Well, we were colluding back then too.
確かにｗ 結託はしてたね。
True lol. We were definitely colluding.
ありがとう、レンくん。
Thank you, Len-kun.
じゃあそして、2度目ましての、猫汰つな！
And then, meeting for the second time, Nekota Tsuna!
さきぶりです！猫汰つなです！
It's been a while! I'm Nekota Tsuna!
あ、じゃあさっき話した...
Ah, so the thing we talked about earlier...
そうだね。さっき話したけど、最近はAPEXをよくやってます。
Right. We talked earlier, but lately I've been playing a lot of APEX.
はい！やってるんだ。よろしくお願いします！
Yes! You are. Nice to meet you!
今度一緒に、なんか教えてほしい、ゲーム。
Next time, I want you to teach me some games.
え！いいよ、全然。やろう。
Eh! Sure, anytime. Let's do it.
うまいもんね！あ、流石に。
You're good at it! As expected.
ということで、いっぱい教えてもらう配信をしたいと思うんですけど...
So, I'd like to do a stream where I learn a lot from you...
以上、ガイル村のメンバーで...
That's all for the Guile Village members—
おい！以上じゃない！びっくりした！
Hey! That's not all! You surprised me!
あｗ ごめんなさいｗ あーｗ なんて自己紹介しようか今必死に考えてたから。
Oh lol, sorry. Ah, I was desperately thinking about how to introduce you just now.
アキロゼさんをガイル村に連れてきた男、ホロスターズ所属、アルランディスです。
The man who brought Aki-rose to Guile Village, Arurandeisu from Holostars.
今日はよろしくお願いいたします。
Nice to meet you today.
そうなんだよね！実はね、こんな扱いしてるけど...
That's right! Actually, even though I'm treating him like this...
なんで全員引いてるの？ｗ
Why is everyone backing away? lol
いやいやｗ サニサニサイモンじゃなくて平気？
No, no lol. Is it okay that you're not Soni Soni Simon?
いやサニサニサイモンは、ほら、ガイルに困ってる人のところに訪れる妖精だから。あれは。
No, Soni Soni Simon is, you know, a fairy who visits people struggling with Guile. That's what he is.
全然俺は知らない、あの人のことは全然。俺じゃないから。
I don't know him at all. He's not me.
あの妖精ちょっとタチ悪いけどね。
That fairy has a bit of a nasty attitude, though.
でも、アキさん本当に、公園で彷徨ってるところを村に連れてきて...
But really, I found Aki-san wandering in a park and brought her to the village...
彷徨ってたんだｗ 公園で彷徨ってたｗ
Wandering? lol She was wandering in a park.
危ない公園で彷徨ってたから、迎えに来たんだよね。
She was wandering in a dangerous park, so I went to pick her up.
そうｗ こんなとこにいるんじゃないよ、って。
Exactly lol. He said, "Don't stay in a place like this."
どんな立場なんだおまえｗ
Who do you think you are? lol
でもこんな扱いしてるけど、ガイル村に引き連れてきてくれた恩人ということでね。
But even though I treat him like this, he's the benefactor who brought me to Guile Village.
あー、素晴らしいｗ 呼んでいただきました。ありがとうございます。
Ah, wonderful lol. Thank you for coming.
ガイル村も、先月か。eスポーツアワード流行語大賞2024も受賞したし。
And Guile Village, was it last month? It won the eSports Award Buzzword Award 2024.
いや、そう、すごい！おめでたい、マジで。
Yeah, right, it's amazing! Truly a celebration.
すごいよね。だってそんなグローバルだったんだｗ びっくりしちゃった。
It is. I didn't know it was so global lol. I was surprised.
すごいよね。だから今年もね、ガイル村でなんか色々...
Amazing. So this year too, with Guile Village, let's do various things...
なんか遊んだりとかもできたらいいよね。
...and it would be great if we could play together.
なんかアキロゼさん、このゲームやろうよ、みたいに言ってたっすよね。
Aki-rose-san, you were saying something like "Let's play this game," right?
そうそう！でもなんか新年会呼ばれない...ｗ
Right, right! But somehow I didn't get invited to the New Year's party... lol
じゃあ今日はありがとう！また遊ぼうね！誕生日おめでとう、ありがとう！
Well, thank you for today! Let's play again! Happy Birthday, thank you!
ようこそお越しなすったご主人様
Welcome, dear master.
隣座ってせーの
Sit next to me, and... one, two...
萌え　萌え　萌え　萌え
Moe moe moe moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would even be happy with this?
ねえ教えて笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me with a smile, up-pu-pu
愛想忘れてご苦労様
Good work on forgetting your manners.
私とあなたでせーの
You and I, and... one, two...
ラッパッパ
Ra-ppa-ppa
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would even be happy with this?
ねえ教えて笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me with a smile, up-pu-pu
ひらりほらり女の子
Fluttering and dancing girl.
ふわりふわり言葉の層
Gently floating layers of words.
それってつまりお冷めな子
That just means you're a cold child.
感情的リアル笑顔でアップップ
Emotional and real, smile and up-pu-pu.
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't always what they seem.
嘘を嘘だと見抜けない
You can't even spot a lie.
仕方ないわねその代わり
I guess it can't be helped, but in exchange...
あー鳥肌鮫肌アップップ
Ah, goosebumps, rough skin, up-pu-pu.
間違ったお仕置きをいただきます
I'll receive a misguided punishment.
私とあなたでせーの
You and I, and... one, two...
ラッパッパ
Ra-ppa-ppa
今夜はド派手にご苦労様
Good work on being flashy tonight.
遊びましょう笑顔でアップップ
Let's play with a smile, up-pu-pu.
ひらりほらりここはどこ
Fluttering and dancing, where is this?
ふわりふわり悟りましょう
Gently floating, let's attain enlightenment.
それってつまりお冷めな子
That just means you're a cold child.
感情的リアル笑顔でアップップ
Emotional and real, smile and up-pu-pu.
歌いだす　秘密の陰
The secret shadow begins to sing.
終わることのないこの世界
In this world that never ends.
悲しい子供は　虚しい子供は
Sad children, empty children...
眠らせて
Let them sleep.
おままごと遊びましょう笑顔でアップップ
Let's play house with a smile, up-pu-pu.
ひらりほらり女の子
Fluttering and dancing girl.
ふわりふわり言葉の層
Gently floating layers of words.
それってつまりお冷めな子
That just means you're a cold child.
感情的リアル笑顔でアップップ
Emotional and real, smile and up-pu-pu.
遊びましょう笑顔でアップップ
Let's play with a smile, up-pu-pu.
アップップ
Up-pu-pu.
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
どうもようこそ。
Welcome, everyone.
はい、いらっしゃいました。
Yes, thank you for coming.
どうも初めまして。
Nice to meet you for the first time.
初めまして！
Nice to meet you!
ちょ、ちょっと...
Wait, a bit...
すみません、なんかあまり近づいちゃいけないかなと思って。
Sorry, I thought maybe I shouldn't get too close.
ということでね、じゃあ「モエチャッカしてみたチャンネル」より...
So, from the 'Moechakka Shitemita Channel'...
ご覧の皆様、はい。「モエチャッカした」...
To everyone watching, yes, 'Moechakka-ed'...
「モエチャッカランディス」と。
I'm Moechakka Randis.
「モエチャッカオウガ」です。
And I'm Moechakka Oga.
はい。ありがとうございます、来てくれて。
Yes. Thank you for coming.
いやいやいや、もうそりゃご用命あらば。
No, no, no, if you have a request for us...
もう呼ばれたらどこへでも行きますよ。
We'll go anywhere we're called.
パッと出てきてパッと帰りますんでね。
We show up fast and leave fast.
仕事人だな、それは。
Quite the professionals, then.
ところでアキロゼさんって、あれですよね、エルフと...
By the way, Akirose-san, you're an elf and...
セイレーンのハーフ。
A half-siren.
よしよしよし。
Alright, alright, alright.
あの、今ってちょっとセンシティブかもしれないけど...
Um, this might be a bit sensitive now, but...
なんだい？なんでも呼んで。
What is it? Ask me anything.
距離感測りすぎじゃない？
Aren't you gauging the distance too much?
お、お年齢って、どんな感じなんですか？
How old are you, exactly?
えー、確かに。どういう...
Oh, true. What's...
そんなレディに、お年齢の話とか...
Asking a lady about her age...
えーっと、両手で数えられる...
Well, I can count it on both hands...
デビューが200歳と、プラス17で、217。
I was 200 years old at debut, plus 17 makes 217.
で、アキロゼは1年に1歳歳をとって、みんなと同じ時間を生きてるんで。
And Akirose ages one year every year,
living the same time as everyone.
つまり、7回目の誕生日だから、224！
So, it's my 7th birthday, which makes me 224!
速い。224歳。
Fast. 224 years old.
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
まだまだ若造だな。
Still a youngster.
2で割れます。
It's divisible by 2.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
まだまだ若造だね。
You're still just a kid.
あ、そっか。そうだよ。魔神だから長いんだ。
Ah, right. That's true.
Being a Majin, you live a long time.
そっか。何歳なの？お父様。
Right. How old are you, Oga-sama?
5000何歳。
Five thousand and something.
やばい。超先輩だった。
Wow. He's a huge senior.
えぐいな。そりゃその貫禄出るわ。
That's crazy. No wonder you have that presence.
ってなると？
And that makes you...?
いや、俺20代でやってるから。
No, I'm doing this in my 20s.
20代！？
20s!?
ぼっちゃ20代！？
Boccha is in his 20s!?
20代でやってる。ここ多分平均取ったらえぐいことになると思う。
I'm in my 20s. If we take the average here,
it'll be insane.
えぐいこと... すごいことになるよ。
Insane... It'll be something else.
平均3000歳とか？
Average 3000 years old?
3000、そう、なる。2500ちょいとかになるかな。
3000, yeah, it would. Around 2500 or so.
俺のせいじゃん。だいぶオーガに引っ張られることになるかもしれない。
That's my fault. I might be pulling the average
up quite a bit.
でもね、今回はこの3人でね、「モエチャッカ」歌ってみたということで。
But this time, the three of us sang 'Moechakka'.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
オーガ肉のね、低音ボイスがこの曲は絶対合うんじゃないかと。
I thought Oga's low-pitched voice
would definitely suit this song.
でも難しかったよ。
But it was difficult.
難しかった。でも頑張ってくれたよね。
It was hard. But you did your best.
ダンスも難しかった、実は。
The dance was also difficult, actually.
確かに。ダンス。でも良かった、踊れたし。
True. The dance. But I'm glad we could do it.
この曲ね、よく聞いてたから俺。
I used to listen to this song a lot.
歌えたの嬉しい。
I'm happy I could sing it.
本当！？なかなかね、メイドさんのキャラクターの歌だから。
Really!? Well, it is a song about
a maid character.
ね、男一人じゃ歌わないから。
Yeah, it's not a song a guy would sing alone.
そう、こうやって呼んでもらわないと歌えないような曲だったから。
Right, it's the kind of song we couldn't sing unless we were invited like this.
やっぱ、我々基本踊るときって、男だけで踊るから。
Usually, when we dance, it's just us guys.
そうね。
That's true.
そうだよね。
Right.
ちょっと珍しい感じがして楽しかったですね。
It felt a bit unusual and was fun.
あー、よかったよかった。
Ah, I'm glad, I'm glad.
ありがとうございました、本当に。
Thank you very much, really.
ね、だからこういう形でやるの、アキポルも初めてだから。
Yeah, it's also the first time for Akiporu to do it like this.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, is that so?
そうなんだ。
Yeah.
そうなんだ、へー。
Is that so, wow.
じゃあなんか、そんなチャレンジな日に呼んでもらった、みたいな感じなんですね。
So, it feels like we were invited on such a challenging day.
そう、で、3人にはね、結構共通点もあって。
Right, and the three of us have quite a few things in common.
ほう？
Oh?
なんと、3人、A、A、A、A、A、A...
Surprisingly, the three of us... A, A, A, A, A, A...
あー！トリプルA！
Ah! Triple A!
確かに、みんなね、あ、から始まるからね。
Certainly, everyone's name starts with 'A'.
荒上...
Aragami...
アキロゼ...
AkiRose...
アルランディス。
Arurandeis.
おおー！
Ohhh!
さらに！
Furthermore!
さらに！？まだあるんだ。
Furthermore!? There's more?
イメージカラーは、え？
The image colors are...?
グリーンですけど。
Mine is green.
あ、わたくしもグリーンで。
Ah, mine is also green.
アキポルもグリーン。
Akiporu is also green.
あー！全員緑！
Ah! Everyone is green!
全員緑や、あ、確かに今、照明もね。
Everyone is green. Ah, certainly, even the lighting now...
あ、そっか、確かにね。
Ah, I see. You're right.
グリーンになってるから。
...has turned green.
ね、みんな、いいでしょ？自然に馴染んでるでしょ？
See? Isn't it great? We're blending in naturally, right?
確かに。
Certainly.
そうなんです、実は。なんでその3人で、考えて。リクエストをしました。
That's right, actually. That's why I thought of these three and made the request.
あー、そっか、そんな共通点あったんだ。俺。
Ah, I see. I didn't know we had those things in common.
ちゃんと考えてたんだ、安心したわ。
You'd actually thought it through. I'm relieved.
おい！考えてなさそうに見えてるっていう話かい。
Hey! Are you saying I looked like I hadn't thought about it?
いやいやいや...
No, no, no...
もう一回燃やしに行く？
Shall I go and set you on fire again?
おそろし、おそろし、おそろし...
Terrifying, terrifying, terrifying...
どんどん、どんどん燃やしに行ってください。
Please go ahead and set me on fire more and more.
歓迎なんだ。
So it's a welcome thing.
いや、でも本当にありがとうございました。なんか。
No, but really, thank you so much.
めったにない機会だったから。
Because it was a rare opportunity.
ね、そうだよね。初めてだったもんね、このメンツで。
Right, yeah. It was the first time for this group.
俺たちも楽しかったです。じゃあ...
We had fun too. Well then...
まだあるんですよね？
There's still more, right?
まだ、ある！
There's still more!
よし！じゃあちょっと、これからも頑張ってください。もっと燃やしてください。
Alright! Well then, please keep doing your best. Please set us on fire more.
いや、本当に、じゃあ本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます！
No, really, then, Happy Birthday for real!
ありがとう、ありがとうねー。
Thank you, thank you!
バイバーイ、ありがとうございましたー。
Bye-bye, thank you very much!
またストプロもやりましょー。
Let's do 'SutoPro' again too!
あー、またねー。
Ah, see you later!
俺たち左右にハケてくから。バイバーイ。
We're exiting to the left and right. Bye-bye.
バイバーイ。
Bye-bye.
見えないところで合流するから。
We'll meet up where you can't see us.
新しいな。
That's new.
Driver's High / 作詞: hyde 作曲: tetsu
Driver's High / Lyrics: hyde Composition: tetsu
熱くなった 銀のメタリックハート
The silver metallic heart has grown hot
導火線に火をつけてあげる
I'll light the fuse for you
不思議なほど ハイな気分さ
I feel high to a strange degree
砂埃を巻き上げて行こう
Let's go, kicking up a cloud of dust
悲鳴を混じらせ 暴走する鼓動
Mixing with screams, a racing heartbeat
目の前には ミサイルの雨
Before my eyes is a rain of missiles
アドレナリン ずっと流して
Keep the adrenaline flowing
僕のほうが オーバーヒートしそう
I think I'm the one who's going to overheat
爆発して 灰になっても
Even if I explode and turn to ash
このままだと 笑ってるね きっと
I'll surely be laughing if it stays like this
街を追い越して この世の果てまで
Passing the town, to the end of the world
ぶっ飛ばして心中しよう さあ 手を伸ばして
Let's speed off and die together, now reach out your hand
地平線に 届くように
So that it reaches the horizon
限界まで 振り切ってくれ
Push it to the limit for me
Woah! Crash! Into the rolling morning
Flash! I'm in the coolest Driver's High
最高のフィナーレを Yeah!
To the ultimate finale, yeah!
もう数えるくらいで 僕らは消え失せて
In just a few counts, we'll vanish
真っ暗な朝が来るね
And a pitch-black morning will come
お気に入りの服に さあ着替えたなら
Once you've changed into your favorite clothes
駆け出して!
Start running!
呆れるほど 声をあげて
Cry out until it's shocking
大気圏を 突破しようぜ
Let's break through the atmosphere
Woah!
Oh, clash! It was a rolling morning
Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high
鋼の翼で
On wings of steel
駆け抜けてよ　時間切れまで
Run through until the time runs out
生まれつきのスピード狂なのさ
I'm a speed freak from birth
Wow! Clash! Into the rolling morning.
Flash! I'm in the coolest driver's high.
Raise me up again! Oh yeah!
わー！
Whoa!
おめでとうー！おめでとうー！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ありがとうー！ということで…
Thank you! So...
今日はスバルちゃんと
Today, Subaru-chan
ししろん、ぼたんちゃんに来てもらいました！
and Shishiron, Botan-chan, are here!
わーい！
Yay!
おめでたい！おめでたい！おめでたい！
Congratulations! It's worth celebrating!
や、もうこの面子と言えば…
Well, when it comes to this group...
はい。
Yes.
薄々分かったよ。
I had a feeling.
私は薄々分かったよ。
I had a hunch.
本当？
Really?
まあ、これとかもあったし。
Well, we had this too.
これね、これ。
This, right.
こんなんしてたし。
We were doing this.
これね、これね。
This, right.
これ、これもね。
This too, right.
まあなんとなくだけどね。
Just a hunch though.
はい。ホロGTAでね、
Yes. In Holo GTA,
まあギャングと警察でバチバチやり合った仲ということで。
we were at each other's throats as gangs and police.
おー！
Oh!
今回『Driver's High』を一緒に歌わせていただきました。
We sang 'Driver's High' together this time.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございますー。
まあ、その節はどうもどうも、本当に。
Well, thanks for everything back then, really.
いや、こちらこそ。
No, same here.
「お世話になる」って意味ではこっちだ。
In terms of 'being taken care of', that's us.
いや、もうだいぶ…
No, really...
だいぶね、昨年はお世話になりましたよ。
You really helped us out a lot last year.
いっぱい企画もやったりとかもしたしね。
We did a lot of projects together too.
確かに、確かに。
True, true.
確かに、そうね。
That's true.
コラボとかも、ちょっとずつ…
Collabs too, little by little...
そうだよう！
That's right!
この後なんかいろいろゲームやったもんね。
We played various games after that, right?
そうだよう！
That's right!
やったし、さ。覚えてる？
We did. Remember?
あの、とんでもなく野生の味を知りにさ…
Going to get a taste of the incredibly wild...
あー！
Ah!
野生味のあるワイルドな！
The wild taste with a sense of wildness!
ワイルドなごはん屋さんに行ったんだよね。
We went to a wild restaurant, didn't we?
あー、はいはいはい。
Ah, right, right.
なんかラッコラーメンみたいなね。
Like sea otter ramen or something.
え？
Eh?
ラッコ食べてたっけ？
Were we eating sea otter?
ほうほう。
I see.
トドせいかもしれない。
Maybe it was sea lion.
ダメだよ、もう！
Stop it already!
ぼたんちゃんも、じゃあワイルドな奴食べに行こう。
Then let's go eat wild stuff with Botan-chan too.
行きたい！
I want to go!
もうなんか寿司とか肉以外食べたいわ。
I want to eat something other than sushi or meat.
おいおい、マジでやべえぞあそこは。
Hey, hey, it's seriously crazy there.
マジで？
Really?
マジか？
Seriously?
現地点取ったから。マジでヤバいぞ。
I've been there. It's seriously crazy.
連れてって。
Take me there.
本当？
Really?
しばらく磯の味抜けないから。
The taste of the sea won't leave you for a while.
何食べたんだよ！
What did you eat?!
だからトド、トド。
I'm telling you, sea lion, sea lion.
トドラーメン。
Sea lion ramen.
怖いわ。
That's scary.
トドラーメン。
Sea lion ramen.
まあ、そんな感じでね、
Well, in that way,
今日をきっかけにして、もっともっと今年は…
starting from today, even more this year...
おー！
Oh!
遊べたら嬉しいなと思ってるので、よろしくお願いします。
I hope we can hang out more, so please be good to me.
よろしくね、アキちゃん。
Let's do it, Aki-chan.
ありがとー。
Thank you.
まあみんなも誘ってよ。
Well, invite everyone too.
誘ってよ！
Invite us!
誘ってよ、ねえ。
Invite us, come on.
分かったよ。
Got it.
本当、富士急の、あのお化け屋敷行こうよ。
Seriously, let's go to that haunted house at Fuji-Q.
嫌だ！
No!
何で？何で？
Why? Why?
嫌だー！
No way!
何でさ？流されなかったから、もう。
Why? I didn't get swayed.
お化け屋敷行こう！
Let's go to the haunted house!
何で？
Why?
何でなの？
Why is that?
無理！
Impossible!
何ででも富士急限定なんだよ。
Why is it specifically Fuji-Q anyway?
え、なんか一番怖いって聞くから、
Well, I heard it's the scariest,
行ってみたい。
so I want to go.
こういうおめでたい場で知れっと言えばいけるかなと思ったけど、
I thought if I casually brought it up at such a happy occasion, it might work,
ダメだったね。
but it didn.
難しかったな。
That was tough.
ごはんから始めて、
Let's start with food,
謎解きとかね。
and then escape rooms or something.
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
はい。
Okay.
ということで、ああ、もっと本当は喋ってたいのに、
So, ah, I really want to talk more, but
時間が！
time is...!
早い！
Fast!
早い早い。
Fast, fast.
ヤバいヤバい。
Oh boy, oh boy.
でもアキちゃん、今年もよろしくお願いします。
But Aki-chan, please be good to me this year too.
お願いしますー。
Please.
こちらこそ、お願いします。
Same here, please.
本当におめでとう！
Truly, congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
またねー！
See you later!
See you!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
え、どっち？
Eh, which way?
じゃあこっち行こう。
Okay, let's go this way.
こっち行こう。
Let's go this way.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Hi rose and girls
絢爛の花園
The glitzy flower garden
上層の高さを
The height of the upper layers
まだ測ってんの？
Are you still measuring?
今だ待ってんの？
Are you still waiting?
違う　乗ってんの
No, I'm riding
音に乗ってんの
Riding on the sound
人生は薔薇色
Life is rose-colored
信じた　そう何回も
I believed so, many times
視野濁ってんの？
Is your vision blurred?
お茶濁してんの？
Are you just stalling?
違う　持ってんの
No, I have it
違う持ってんの 願い持ってんの
I have something different... I have a wish...
何処へ行けば見える リアルな茨
Where should I go to see the real thorns?
為せば成るがシンプル 棘
It's simple: where there's a will, there's a way. Thorns.
逃げて 逃げて 逃げて 森奥へ
Run, run, run deep into the forest.
Rose and girls
Oh my gosh!
茨ばっかばっかの 世界だから
Because it's a world full of thorns.
時折夢見 霞むけど
Sometimes I dream and it gets hazy,
でもね待った待ったって 意味ないから
but waiting won't do any good.
無垢なルートに 囚われないように
So I won't be trapped on a pure route,
何色にでもなれるから
because I can become any color.
Hi rose and girls
uh uh uh
Na na na na
Hi rose and girls
今宵歌うよ
Tonight, I'll sing.
野に咲く私を見てて
Watch me blooming in the field.
知恵の果実を
The fruit of knowledge,
淡淡と噛じるの
chewing it nonchalantly.
意味分かってんの 味わってんの
I understand the meaning. I'm tasting it.
これが合ってんのか 分かっていたいの
I want to know if this is right.
擦り剥いた膝 落着エンド
Skinned knees. Settled end.
これからでしょ 咲ければ全免除
It starts now. If I bloom, everything is waived.
闇ゲットー アンメット
Dark ghetto. Unmet.
残機を全Bet
Betting all remaining lives.
皆いる？今何マイル？
Is everyone here? How many miles now?
良ければ教えてくれアイルー
If you'd like, let me know, Airou.
転んでも大丈夫 私がいる
It's okay to fall. I'm here.
誰も彼も同じコーデ
Everyone and everything in the same outfit.
来る日も来る日もお勤め
Working hard day after day.
逃げた 逃げた 逃げた 虚空の方へ
Ran, ran, ran towards the void.
桃源が
Paradise...
桃源があるから
...is there.
茨ばっかばっかの 世界だから
Because it's a world full of thorns.
時折夢見 霞むけど
Sometimes I dream and it gets hazy,
でもね待った待ったって 意味ないから
but waiting won't do any good.
無垢なルートに 囚われないように
So I won't be trapped on a pure route,
何色にでもなれるから
because I can become any color.
Hi rose and girls
uh uh uh
君に歌うよ
I'll sing to you.
虚に咲く私を見てて
Watch me blooming in the void.
アローナ！今お披露目した新曲「茨」、
どうだったかな？
Alona! How was the new song "Ibara"
that I just performed?
この後24時頃から配信サービスでも
聴けるようになるので、
It'll be available on streaming services
starting around 24:00,
ぜひたくさん聴いて感想どしどし
SNSに投稿してください！
so please listen to it a lot and post your
thoughts on social media!
見に行くよ！
I'll go check them out!
ねぇねぇ、そこの君！
チャンネル登録ってもうした？
Hey, hey, you there!
Have you subscribed to the channel yet?
ん、まだだよね。じゃあチャンネル登録ポチ、
高評価もポチ、ついでに通知もオン、ポチ！
Hmm, not yet, right? Then click subscribe,
click like, and click to turn on notifications too!
ということで、まだの人よろしくお願いします！
So, for those who haven't yet, please do!
ちなみにこの後22時30分から
メンバー限定アフターライブもやっちゃうので、
By the way, I'll be doing a members-only
after-live starting from 22:30,
メンバーシップの登録をしてくれた方、
忘れずにぜひこのままレッツゴーしましょう！
for those who have joined the membership,
don't forget and let's go just like this!
待っててね！
Wait for me!
からの、アキロゼ生誕祭2025記念グッズ
発売いたします！
And, we are releasing AkiRose Birthday
Festival 2025 commemorative goods!
待ってたよね！ということで早速紹介していきましょう！
You were waiting for this, right! So let's introduce them right away!
ラインナップはこちら！
Here's the lineup!
今回のライブコンセプト「Your True Colors」を題材に、
Based on the live concept "Your True Colors,"
雪子先生に描いていただきました。
they were illustrated by Yukiko-sensei.
異世界のファンタジー感あるお花屋さんの
女の子をイメージしております。
We're imagining a girl from a fantasy flower shop
in another world.
可愛さと色気を兼ね備えたアキロゼに
ぴったりのイラストになっています。
It's an illustration perfect for AkiRose,
combining cuteness and sexiness.
こちら、キービジュアルが大きくプリントされた、
ワイドラバーマット！
This is the Wide Rubber Mat,
with the key visual printed large!
大きくて使いやすいラバーマット、
色んな使い道ができると思います。飾るもよし使うもよし。
It's a large and easy-to-use rubber mat,
with many uses. Good for decorating or for use.
あなたのパソコン周りにぜひ彩りを添えてください。
Please add some color to your computer desk.
次はこちら、なんとついに出た、
アキロゼとおそろいフルグラフィックTシャツ！
Next is this, it's finally here: an AkiRose
matching Full Graphic T-shirt!
アキロゼのゲーミング衣装のインナーと
おそろいのTシャツになっています。
It's a T-shirt matching the inner layer
of AkiRose's gaming outfit.
ゲーミングパーカーを買ってくれた方は、
これとこれセットにしちゃうとめっちゃいい感じなんじゃないの？
For those who bought the gaming parka,
wouldn't it look great as a set?
もちろんTシャツだけでもめちゃめちゃ目立つし可愛いので、
イベントなどなど色んなところに着たり楽しんじゃってください。
Of course, the T-shirt alone stands out and is cute,
so please wear it to events and enjoy it!
次はこちら、アキロゼのヘッドセンサーヘアクリップ！
Next is this, AkiRose's Head Sensor Hair Clip!
ありそうでなかったアキロゼの身に付けているグッズ、
はい、あなたのお手元に届いちゃいます。
A good based on something AkiRose wears that
didn't exist until now... yes, it can be yours.
アキロゼのヘッドセンサーを再現した
ヘアクリップになってるんだけど、
It's a hair clip that reproduces
AkiRose's head sensor...
髪を留めるのに使ってもよし、色んなものに挟んでもよし、
身に付けてもよし、置いといてもよし。
Good for holding your hair, clipping onto things,
wearing, or just displaying.
アキロゼがそこにいた...
It's like AkiRose was there...
...じゃないかと思わせる痕跡になると思うので、ぜひ色んなね楽しい遊び方をしてください。いっぱいゲットしてね！
...it'll be a trace that makes people think that, so please find various fun ways to use it. Get lots of them!
次は、アキロゼぬいぐるみカードホルダー！アキロゼの顔がついたカードケースになっています。めっちゃ可愛い！お気に入りのカードや、この後紹介する特典チェキも入れられちゃいます。
Next is the AkiRose Plushie Card Holder! It's a card case with AkiRose's face on it. So cute! You can put your favorite cards or the bonus cheki I'll introduce later in it.
さらに今年の誕生日シチュエーションボイスも出ます！あまあま耳かきボイス、台本アキロゼが考えて頑張って撮りました。というか楽しんで撮りました！
Furthermore, this year's birthday situation voice is also coming out! A sweet ear-cleaning voice. AkiRose thought up the script and worked hard to record it. Or rather, I had fun recording it!
そしてなんと今回フルセット特典もあります！フルセット購入特典は、ASMR特典ボイス。タイトルは「アイス食べよっ」、そういうことです。
And guess what? There's a full set bonus this time! The full set purchase bonus is an ASMR bonus voice. The title is "Let's Eat Ice Cream." That's how it is.
そしてもう一つ購入特典は、サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードです。こちら箔押し複製サイン入り。ぜひカードケースに入れて持ち歩いてほしいなって。
And another purchase bonus is a signed cheki-style bromide card. This one has a gold-stamped replica signature. I'd love for you to carry it around in your card case.
え？直筆サインが欲しい？もうなんと、あります！そんなあなたに数量限定バージョンをぜひゲットしてください。数に限りがあるので、お見逃しなく。
Eh? You want a handwritten signature? Well, we have those too! For those of you who do, please get the limited edition version. There's a limited number, so don't miss out.
この後22時20分ショップオープン予定なので、会員登録とか済ませてない人は準備して待っててね！概要欄をチェックチェック！
The shop is scheduled to open at 22:20 later today, so if you haven't registered as a member yet, please get ready and wait! Check, check the description box!
そして今回グッズセットをご購入いただいた方に、昨年9月に発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚特典としてつきます。推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードです。
And this time, those who purchase the goods set will receive one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game released last September as a bonus. It's a key card to show off your favorite, the Oshi Holomen card.
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページで確認してね。カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください。ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となりますので、ご注意ください。
Please check the website for card details and how to play. Please note that the cards will be in Japanese only. This only applies to those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop, so please be careful.
以上、誕生日記念グッズでした。この後メンバー限定のアフターライブもあるので、よろしければメンバー登録もよろしくお願いします。
That's it for the birthday commemoration goods. There's also a members-only after-live later, so please consider joining the membership as well.
それでは、ライブの締めくくり、エンディングありますので、ぜひ最後まで見ていってくださいね。今日のライブの感想もぜひたくさん呟いてね！
Now, we have the ending to close the live, so please watch until the very end. Please tweet lots of your thoughts on today's live too!
それでは、Your True Colorsのエンディング、ご覧ください。
Now, please watch the ending for 'Your True Colors'.
モノクロの世界に囚われてしまっていた彼女の心は、
Her heart, which had been trapped in a monochrome world,
様々な花たちやお客様との触れ合いを経て、
through interactions with various flowers and customers,
当たり前の日常はいつも自分のそばにあって、何よりも大切、ということに気づきました。
realized that the ordinary daily life is always by her side and is more important than anything else.
そんな大切なたくさんの思い出の中で、
In the midst of those many precious memories,
笑顔をもらっていたのは自分だけじゃなく、自分もみんなを笑顔にしていたことを彼女は知りました。
she learned that it wasn't just her receiving smiles, but she was also making everyone else smile.
「色んな色があって、それが自分らしくていいんだ」
"There are many colors, and that's what makes me, me."
と自分自身の魅力を認めることができました。
She was finally able to accept her own charms.
そしてついに彼女は、今まで以上の輝きを取り戻すことができたのです。
And finally, she was able to regain a brilliance greater than ever before.
このお話は決して彼女だけの物語ではありません。
This story is by no means her story alone.
そう、花屋はいつだってここにある。
Yes, the flower shop is always here.
あなたの心の中に。
Inside your heart.
Birthday 3D LIVE
歌唱楽曲: 「青のすみか」 渋谷ハル、白雪レイド
Song: "Ao no Sumika" Shibuya Hal, Shirayuki Reid
歌唱楽曲: 「ヒアシビ」 癒月ちょこ、八雲べに、本間ひまわり
Song: "Hiashibi" Uzuki Choco, Yakumo Beni, Honma Himawari
歌唱楽曲: 「モエチャッカファイア」 荒咬オウガ、アルランディス
Song: "Mochechaka Fire" Arakami Oga, Arurandeisu
歌唱楽曲: 「Driver's High」 大空スバル、獅白ぼたん
Song: "Driver's High" Oozora Subaru, Shishiro Botan
【振付】 ミユキニシジマ 【サムネイルイラスト】 BORUMETE
[Choreography] Miyuki Nishijima [Thumbnail Illustration] BORUMETE
【ロゴ制作】 ミナトデザイン 【音楽制作】 トライフロンティア合同会社
[Logo Design] Minato Design [Music Production] Tri-Frontier LLC
【MIX・MA】 音響ハウス
[Mix/MA] Onkyohaus
【背景・OL映像制作】 スタジオメイピー
[Background/OL Video Production] Studio Mapy
【OP・EDイラスト制作】 未早 【企画・構成・総合演出】 アキ・ローゼンタール
[OP/ED Illustration] Misaki [Planning/Direction] Aki Rosenthal
[Special Thanks] ロゼ隊 ALL STAFF and You
[Special Thanks] Rose-tai, ALL STAFF and You
Your True Colors Aki Rosenthal 2025 Birthday 3D LIVE